Yeah. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to episode 256 of the Ask
Kabijit show. I hope you're all doing
very well. I just came in over here from
the previous live stream which was
geostrategy episode 4. I suppose many of
you would would have come in from there
as well. So uh before we get going let
me just take a look at who all is there
on the live stream. Okay let me take
this comment before I greet everybody. I
can see Sonia Sha saying I just migrated
from the excellent geio strategy
briefing. Thank you as always Abijit and
your team for all the hard work. Thank
you very much. But let me just uh put
this on the record. There is no team
over here. This is a oneman show. So
there is no Abijit and team. It's just
Abijit who does this. All right. Okay.
Let's take a look at who all is there on
the live chat. Let me greet some of you.
read some of you. I can see kanesh
koshik nabanita das
dyangi
dongrikar uh dongrikar makavin vikas pj
suas redi truthful penguin arush sha
shivasai aayoshav Ichino spai bijes sk
nishant t abhinash acharia shreas mitra
chat dsp sujit sha shaagandha goes ki
devourer of worlds geopolitical Dubai
from Indor by Vanos spot behikar Manisha
Kardoso Vidiar Pariji
Jadikshit Delta OG
vintan Vintan says Vimla Chodri who else
koshik Sumit Agarwal Rahul Dunak Abin
Acharia again Vishu Kumar Kanesh Sai
Sasank Keshav Misra Mishra Uh who else
do we have? Uh let me see who else we
have. S sh Red Ready Keshav
Sharma Bandekar Bhoji Makav again Keshav
Suyash Manisha Matei Moji Pio Africanus.
Okay. Uh, Orbit and Markets, Spart
Patel, Vincent, Vega, Yashika, Jet,
Milani, Chat, DSP, Echo and Lone Walker,
Manger, Pradhan, Ripon, Xenomorph
forces, Super Rex, Karan, Nalawat,
Mastermind, Edtopia, U,
Ankita, Sonia,
Saagan, Chirai, Priyanka, Javalia,
Synica and so many other people. So,
thank you so much for being on the live
chat. I won't be able to greet you all
otherwise it'll just go on forever. So
let me take some of the questions and
let's see what we have. Let's start with
this one. Kumar Kaneshka says as India
is ending red corridor in central India
and cracking down NOS's and their
funding to stop minding in the stop
meddling in the internal affairs of the
country. Is this the re reason why
Pakistan and Bangladesh is getting
geared up against India by the US? Yes,
of course. Look uh how do you keep a
nation down? How do you keep a nation
from growing? How do you keep a nation
from pro progressing? You create all
kinds of internal problems in the
country. Right? So that's what foreign
powers have invested in within India for
decades. They have invested in various
terrorist uh movements. The Kalistthan
movement, the the Kashmir terrorism, the
various terrorist infra insurgencies
that you've had in the NXelite belt and
so on. You had the various you had the
LTT thing. Then you had various
secessionist uh movements in various
parts of the far east of India
northeast. Every state had multiple uh
secessionist out outlets and so on so
forth. Right? Some of these were were
indigenous indigenously homegrown
because of complete neglect by the
government of India. But then foreign
powers stepped in and and funded some of
them. That's also there. So foreign
powers have been doing this for a very
long time. And then they have been
funding uh industrial scale conversions
to foreign religion religions in India.
So all of this has been done for a very
long time in India and uh now that India
has successfully cracked down on many of
these these these activities. Uh there
is no more any there's no Kalistthani
insurgency anymore in Punjab. The
Kashmir situation is very much very
strongly under control.
um the naxelite situation is is on the
verge of being uh resolved and so on. So
obviously when when we are able
to control all of this and we are able
to resolve these these problems then the
foreign powers which want to restrict
our rise they will look at other
alternative uh solutions to the to to
alternative ways of keeping India down.
So that's where East and West Pakistan
come in and that's why you know
Bangladesh is getting more and more uh
US support. Bangladesh is is cooperating
with Pakistan and and synergizing with
Pakistan. Pakistan seems to be receiving
a lot of US support these days. It's
very visible. Trump's companies are
investing in Pakistan in crypto and
whatnot. There are US uh it looks like
the Nurh Khan air air base has been
taken over by the U by the United States
and Pakistan is getting huge IMF and
World Bank bailouts and Bangladesh is
also getting support from other
countries like China and so on. So you
can see the US and and China see eye to
eye on on on one thing which is the need
to keep India down. So you are right
Kumar Kanesh this is the reason why
Pakistan and Bangladesh are being uh
leveraged against against us by the US
as well as China.
Na2 cara okay China/west using social
media to amplify hest uh and amplify
hate between Thai and Kir people on the
border over a Hindu temple a Shiva
temple Tik Tok is spreading anti-Indian
sentiment through unsavory content in
Latin America and West Africa how to
counter
this interesting points that you've
raised
So yeah, this is not a very important
matter from a global geopolitical
geostrategic perspective which is why I
have not discussed the the kair temple
issue but uh why don't we discuss this
this matter there's this border dispute
that's going on between uh China between
I'm sorry Cambodia and Thailand and it's
a long-standing border dispute that
these two nations have and they've
almost gone to war a couple of times
over this one temple. So let us go to
the map and uh let me show what this is
all about. Cambodia and Thailand, two of
our friendly nations, nations that were
for the longest time part of the
indosphere. They still are. Okay. So
here we have this nation called
Thailand. And then we have Cambodia.
They as you can see they have a they
have a significantly long border. Now
let's search for Priya Vihar Temple.
and let's zoom in. So now first let's
zoom out to know exactly where this
is. Okay. So this is where this temple
is located. This is a
1,000-year-old Shiva temple which was
built by Kir King Surya Surya 1 and
Surya Wman 2 if I'm not
mistaken. Uh and let's uh look at the
satellite image.
So there are gopuras over here. And this
is a pretty big temple complex. It's
1,000 years old. It is ruined. It is
ruined. As you can see, it's the it's
it's in the shape of an ancient Hindu
temple. A typical Hindu temple
layout. And here you have another Gura
and all. As you can see, it was a very
big complex back in the
day. And I suppose you can zoom in over
here and you can see what this this uh
structure looks like. As you can see, it
is it's in very bad. It's in a very bad
shape of disrepair. It's very old and
it's in ruins. Now, let's go back to 3D
imagery. Let's reorient ourselves. And
as you can see, this is on top on top of
a hill-like
structure. It's it's kind of a hilly.
It's on top of a hill. Now, this
area this is disputed between Thailand
and Cambodia. As you can see, some part
of it is in Thailand, some part of it is
in Cambodia. Uh Cambodia is the nation
of the is the nation of the Kare
people. So technically Cambodia says
this should be ours but Thailand says
this this temple should be ours. So it's
a deeply revered Shiva temple that both
nations claim. Uh there is no
strategic use to this temple. It has no
strategic importance or significance.
The reason both nations want it is it's
is because it's a very old, very highly
revered Hindu temple. Both nations are
supposed to be Buddhist countries today.
H but both nations have nearly gone to
war over this
temple. Um and apparently China and the
West are using social media to amplify
hate between the two nations over this
over this temple, the Priya Vihar
temple. Um so yeah that's about the
temple but you can see how social media
can be weaponized over these things and
as you say Tik Tok is spreading
anti-India sentiments through uh
unsavory um reels etc in Latin American
countries and in western
Africa you know uh making these these
parody videos of extremely unhygienic
Indian food
preparation
perpetally by Indians or or what
Bangladesh is pre pretending to be
Indians, Indians and so on so forth. And
they're putting out these reals and
these video clips on Tik Tok and this is
creating an impression in these
countries that India is extremely
unhygienic country with super low
standards. Right? This is being done by
Tik Tok. Tik Tok is owned by China. So
how do we counter this? Well, there's my
question is why don't we have our own
social media platform? The US has all
its social media platforms. The Chinese
have Tik Tok. Why hasn't India invested
in a social media platform or some kind
of platform or a news platform of its
own? Why is the government of India
completely clueless and unwilling to
take any action on this?
Why? I I don't get
it. I've been saying this for at least
four years. India needs its own
equivalent of the BBC, the CNN or or or
what what the Middle East has in Al
Jazzer. The Chinese have Global Times
and CCTN and whatnot. Every nation has a
global news outlet. India has
nothing. India is the fourth largest
economy in the world. The Indian
government has super deep pockets, but
it's simply not interested in doing
this. As a consequence, everybody just
walks over India in the war of
narratives. India doesn't have a social
media platform of of its
own. And that's why people can spread
any kind of nonsense on the Chinese
social media platforms, the on the
American social media platforms about
us. How can we counter this? Well, we
will have to fight the war on these
foreign platforms. So, Indians should
make their own
reels showing how wonderful India is.
and we are more in
number right so if if let's say 10% of
Indians or let's say 1% of Indians do
this h so out of 1.4 4 billion. If 14
million Indians put out one reel in a
week, then you will have 14 million
reels. Okay, looks like there was some
kind of connection issue, but we are
back. I think I was talking about social
media and the need for India to have its
own social media and looks like someone
did not like it very much and which is
why it kind
of Yeah. Well, that's interesting, isn't
it? Okay, so
yeah, once again, where was I? I kind of
lost that that comment I was talking
about. Anyway, I I hope I kind of
answered that.
Okay, we go on to the next question by
Zan HZ Gaming. With will the LA
anti-eportation riots become national or
out of control? Does the amount of
support for illegals and foreign flags
at protests show that America is losing
control of land taken from Mexico? Well,
Los Angeles is land taken from Mexico
for sure. uh there's a whole
u history behind this in which I have
which I have kind of discussed or I am
in the process of discussing it in u the
understanding America podcast but let's
take a look at this let me put the put
the map on the screen when you talk
about uh land taken from Mexico I don't
think most people today will understand
what we mean by that so let's let's go
to the
maps let's go to the map let's go to the
US now you have these two nations. In
North America, you have three nations.
You have Canada, you have the US, and
you have Mex Mexico. And in Mexico, you
have this place called Baja California.
This entire long region is called Baja
California. Why is it called Baja
California? Because it's part of the
larger California region. If you look at
California in the US, you will see these
these cities which have Spanish names.
San Diego, Santa Monica, Santa Barbara,
San Jose, San Francisco, Sacramento, Los
Angeles, Las Vegas and so
on. All these lands were part of
Mexico. Then you have
Arizona, Phoenix, uh sorry. So even
Arizona was part of of uh
Mexico. And when it comes to Nevada,
Nevada also most likely if I recall was
part of Mexico and so was New Mexico,
Albuquerqueke and so on and so
forth. So and even DeAs, Texas. So a lot
of this territory belonged to Mexico. It
was taken, it was annexed by the US in
the middle of the 19th century in the US
Mexico war and they gave a little bit of
money to Mexico to make it official, you
know, to make it sound legal like we've
not stolen your land but we've paid you
for it. That sort of thing. And they
took all this land from Mexico. So it's
stolen land, annexed land, but they won
it in a war. So they say it's it's by
right of conquest that they have it. And
the whole continent was stolen from from
the natives by massacring them,
genociding them, and putting the rest in
concentration camps which are called
reservations. So that's what the US is.
That's the kind of nation it is. Now uh
so that is about uh the stolen lands.
That's that matter. Now, will these LA
anti-deportation riots spiral out of
control? Will they become a national
issue? Well, it depends on how much
political support they
have. If the Democratic Party decides to
support the this issue, then this could
spring up everywhere in the country. The
Republicans don't support this. The
Democrats support immigration and all
that. We know what the Biden
administration's policy was just a few
months ago. They had opened the southern
border with Mexico those past four years
and they allowed as many illegals to as
as as they wanted to come into the
country and now Trump's Trump's admin
administration is trying to deport these
illegals. So Biden allows a few million
to come in over four years. Now Trump is
trying to reverse that and send them all
out of back out of the US.
Incredible what's going on in the US. I
mean what sort of seessawing of policy
is this right?
Um so whether the riots become a
national issue, whether they go out of
control depends on the the approach of
the Democratic party. If they support
it, this could very much become a
national issue and this could very much
spiral out of control.
Um does the amount of support for
illegals and foreign flags at protests
show that US is losing control of land
taken from Mexico? I don't I don't think
it's losing control of the lands taken
stolen from Mexico, but it looks like
there is a significant percentage of the
US population close to 50% perhaps that
is in favor of opening the borders and
allowing illegals to come into the
country. Looks like that. So the people
who vote for the Democrats, they
typically are in favor of
immigration and opening the border and
so on so forth. So that is close to 50%
I would say.
So yeah that's that's that's true that
is
real. Uh Baratia says how long do you
think how long do you feel it will take
for the Indis waters treaty obeyance to
show real effects on Pakistan as hydro
projects are long-term
measures? How to further fasttrack our
gain of control besides defense
upgrades? Um so look this is a slow
burning thing and the longer this
remains in force the obeyance or
whatever you want to call it the more
and more it's going to start
pressurizing Pakistan
uh see we have a number of runof the
river projects that are already
operational by which we can even
according to the the indust treaty
itself according to the treaty itself we
can use some of the water hold it in
reservoirs for some time and then
release it back. That itself can have a
certain effect. It can it can make the
flow of water to Pakistan unpredictable.
So sometimes we can withhold water for
for a significant amount of time and
then we can release it all at once. So
Pakistan doesn't get to use it properly.
That sort of thing. And then we have
other dams that are currently being
constructed that that will be able to
hold even more water. So there's a
number of dams. One will become
operational next year. Then there's
going to be more becoming operational by
2028, 29, 2030, 2031. And now we're
going to start multiple new projects I
suppose and start building canals that
will essentially recreate the route of
the ancient river Sarasbati and uh you
know take the waters of the uh Synindhu
basin and reroute them in canals across
Rajasthan all the way to Katch all these
regions in western India that that have
had shortages of water ever since the
Saraspati disappeared. So we could
recreate the route of the ancient
Saraspati by creating this this canal
system and this could take let's say 10
years. So every year that passes the
pressure is going to become like 5% 5%
more on Pakistan sometimes 10% more and
over 10 years it becomes almost 100%. At
least 50% more. So every year that
passes the Pakistanis will feel the
squeeze more and more. It's not going to
happen overnight. It's going to be
gradual, almost imperceptible, but every
year it's going to get worse for
Pakistan unless they cooperate, unless
they demonstrate that they want to give
up terrorism and they prove they show
demonstrable, verifiable proof that they
are taking specific actions against the
terrorists, eliminating the known
terrorists. Eliminating means
eliminating dismantling all the terror
infra infrastructure, handing over all
the wanted terrorists to India and so on
so forth. Fourth, we can tell them
exactly what the what are the steps that
we we require and if they do that well,
we'll be happy to once again start
releasing water as per maybe a new
treaty or maybe the old treaty. We we
can see about that. Yeah. But at this
point in time because Pakistan is not
changing its approach and it's serving
as a mercenary to anti anti-India
forces. So we're going to continue this.
So it's going to take time but we
already have a significant amount of
leverage in Pakistan. We already can uh
ruin Pakistani crops. Sad to say this
but this is where we are today because
of Pakistan's fault, because of
Pakistan's long-standing support of
terrorism. That's why we have to do
these things. Otherwise we would never
never do this. So we are in a position
to already cause significant uh damage
to Pakistan and every year that passes
it's going to get worse in 10 years it's
going to be unbearable for
Pakistan. So that's where we are. So
yeah we need to get going on all these
measures. We need to start building that
that canal infrastructure and all and
that can definitely be done properly in
the next 10 years. So by 2035 Pakistan
will be in dire straits if they haven't
mended their
ways. Uh Shivanch says what do you think
about Mayar dynasty and Baba Raal's
empire which ended up resisting Islamic
invasion for more than 500 years. Look
Baba Raal's empire did not end did not
resist Islamic invasion for 500 years.
Um Bapar Raal was a great warrior. Uh
he's supposed to be a semi semi-leendary
warrior or something like that. That's
what the historians claim, right?
Um so he was a warrior u a Rajput
warrior and he reclaimed some of the
lands we had lost to the
Turks and he founded the city that still
bears his name Rahul Pindi which we have
given away to Pakistan and it is now the
the epicenter of the Pakistani military
complex military ISI terrorism complex
Rahul Pindi right so that city is named
after him. So he reclaimed that part of
our our homeland which the Turks had
taken over. But now it's again gone back
to the Turks. I mean to the to those who
claim to be the descendants of the
Turks. Uh and Babar's career ended
somewhere else. So after he did all
this, after he you know he pacified the
Turks and expelled them from from our
lands, then he retired with his warriors
and he went north to the Himalayas and
he became a a disciple of Baba
Goraknath and he and his men because of
their wor their reverence of Baba
Goraknath came to be known as the
Gorcas and their descendants are today's
Gorcas who are mainly found in northern
India and Nepal.
Uh so that's what I can tell you that's
how much I know about Paparal. I don't
know a lot about the Maywa dynasty so I
won't be able to give you further
details about that but uh thank you for
the question and that gave me the
opportunity to give to speak a little
about Baparel. Great man great
warrior. Uh Arun says and it's a great
question by Arun. Why are we still going
ahead with Starlink after the Elon Musk
Donald Trump breakup? Does India predict
that they will get back again like any
other toxic
relationship? You know there's a
possibility my friends that uh they may
be they may be faking this. It may be a
fake
fight to to draw out the
enemies, you know. So it's it's this
these things happen. These things have
been done in the past. two best friends
pretend to fight very viciously very
publicly for a certain period of time so
that they can see who all tries to take
advantage of the situation and then they
again join hands and then they defeat
the enemies who have shown their true
faces. Okay, so there's always the
possibility that this may be a fake
fight, a
staged
fight. Now when it comes to
Starlink, it's bad for us. No question
about it. It's terrible for us. It's
terrible for India's
sovereignty. I've spoken about this
yesterday. I've spoken about this many
times. It'll allow terrorists and riers
to have unrestricted internet access
from the skies even if the government
decides to switch off the internet
services because Elon Musk won't listen
to India. He will say you can shake your
fists at the sky. He has tweeted that in
the past about some other
country. So when once Starling becomes
operational, it's going to be that sort
of situation. terrorists all over the
country whether they are terrorists in
Kashmir, terrorists in in cookie in in
cookie occupied India or
terrorists wherever else in in the Naxal
areas or whatever else you know they
could act with operate with impunity
riers in various parts of India could
operate with impunity and this could uh
end up compromising India's security and
sovereignty so I don't think Starlink is
a good idea for India I I think India
should become a competitor to Starlink.
I think
maybe maybe Jio maybe the Adani group
maybe they should launch their own
constellation of satellites a better
more powerful more capable constellation
of satellites as a competition as a
competitor to Elon Musk Starlink and tie
up with ISRO to do this. give us snow
five years to develop reusable launch
vehicles and so on and the capability to
launch large large quantities of
satellites at the same time large big
satellites not small ones at the same
time. So that will be a huge boost for
ISO it will be a huge boost for India
and within 5 to 10 years India will be a
major challenger and a major and
probably better alternative to Starling
globally. That's what we should
do. We should not go with with Starling.
It's it's bad for India. That's what I
that's my
opinion. Um but I don't know. I think
it's still early days. Uh India acts
very slowly, very deliberately. Maybe
there's a good reason for that. Yeah.
And maybe we are considering the
possibility that this is a fake breakup.
Maybe they are pretending. Maybe they're
trying to see who the enemies are. But
overall, we should not have said yes to
Starling in the first place. Uh but
let's see how this goes. Yeah.
Fjasma says, "Do you think India can
prosper if they become if we become a
dictatorship like China? Because it
feels like democracy has caused a lot of
problems." I think I answer this at
least once in every liveream. I agree.
We have experimented with democracy. Uh
let's experiment with something
different. I am not I'm not I'm not
saying we should have a dictatorship, a
secular dictatorship. I think uh what
has served us best
civilizationally for thousands of years
is a monarchy system and that's the
system that's been in place all over the
world and the world is going back to
that sort of imperial system slowly but
gradually. What is the US? It's an
empire. It's not really a democracy.
It's a two-party system with a single
agenda which is masquerading as a
democracy. It's just one step above
above a one party system like China
which is another empire and Mr. Xiinping
is the is the emperor. Okay. The CCP is
a dynasty and then we have Russia which
is again going towards the imperial
system. So we have the slow reemergence
of
empires. So maybe India should start the
transition by transitioning to a
presidential form of government with
maybe an 8-year cycle, 10ear cycle that
sort of thing. And if it works better
then transition to something even more
robust. So I think India will certainly
do much better that way.
I am I'm sure it will because
historically we had dictatorships,
didn't we? Every single king of ours,
every single emperor of ours, the ones
who we rever today, who are they? They
were dictators, weren't they? They were
not elected democratically. Nobody dared
to say that they should be brought down.
So
yeah, Pervvin Singh says, "So many
recctor 4 earthquakes in Pakistan in the
last few days. Are American nukes being
detonated in a controlled way? Can it be
the main reason for pausing operation
Synindor? Okay, let's take a look at
this question. Let me try and do some
live analysis. Okay. Uh let's let's
earthquake
earthquake tracker. Let's take a look at
latest
earthquakes. Uh which one should I see?
map of um let's say the USGS thing.
Okay. Do they have list of
earthquakes in the past let's say past
day? Do you have it over the past let's
say one week? Not sure. There's nothing
uh in the subcontinent apart from this
one. Wow. It's in Burma Tandu. But I
would like it for today. Okay. Let's go
back. Let's go back to the Google
search. Let's see this one. I would like
to see earthquakes in our region in the
subcontinent over the past 7 days, let's
say. And I want to see the depths at
which these earthquakes have happened.
But this girl, this website seems to
take a lot of time to open which okay.
So where do we have this? Gear Sat
Gujarat etc. What do we have in
Pakistan? Okay, this is an Indian site
that's why it's slow. Oh, nice. So what
do we have? Reviewed reviewed
uh what about this one? Dra Kazi Khan
magnitude depth 10 kilometers depth. You
see this my friends this earthquake in
Dra
Kazakhan which happened on the 29th of
May. This earthquake happened at the
depth of 10 kilometers. 10 km below the
surface. What is this here?
Okay, this is the same one. Okay, let's
find some other earthquake which
happened in Pakistan. This is an
earthquake in Jang. Now let's see this
earthquake. It happened on the 27th of
May. It happened at a depth of
kilometers.
Okay, let's see this one. What is this?
It is It happened on the 12th of May at
a depth of 10 kilometers. 10 kilometers.
What is this? This happened on the 10th
of May at a depth of 10 kilometers below
the surface of the
planet. What else do we have? Anything
else? We have something over here. This
one happened
uh in so and so place in Pakistan 30th
of May at a depth of 180 kilometers
below the surface. So let me say this my
friends, no question. Okay, let's see
this one near
Lahore 111 km. All these earthquakes
have magnitudes of between 3 4 whatever
3 4
5. Now understand this. What did we just
see? We
saw where the earthquakes happened all
in Pakistan. We saw the magnitudes
between 3, four, five around that that
sort of thing. And we saw the depth at
which the earthquake originated.
the the
the shallowest depth was 10
km. Humans don't drill holes 10 km
down. Do you
understand? I know you on YouTube all
kinds of experts are saying that
Pakistan is detonating it's uh unstable
nuclear bombs. All sorts of army experts
etc are saying this. But if you look at
the seismic data that we have, the
earthquake data, it tells you at what
depth the earthquake originated. Now
when it says that the earthquake
originated at a depth of 10 kilometers
below the surface, do you think the
Pakistanis have the technology to drill
a hole 10 km deep? They don't. I promise
you
that another earthquake happened at a
depth of 111 11 kilometers.
Nobody has the technology. Another
earthquake 180
km. So most of these earthquakes are
happening way below any human can reach
through current
technology. I think that should answer
the
questions. Maybe some of the earthquakes
could have some other implications but
the ones that just randomly
saw are all at depths that Pakistanis
can't reach through technology.
So, so that for me is enough to tell me
that these are not artificial
earthquakes. Aris Manticor says, "Have
you heard of Pavit Singh? I've heard the
name. He has a YouTube channel and is a
very vehement national security hawk.
Could you check him out? A debate
discussion between the two of you would
be incredible to see." Okay, thank you
so much for the recommendation. I will
check him out. You know, I don't know
how to check him out because I don't
watch podcast. I don't have the time for
that. I have a lot of work to do, a lot
of analyt analytical work to do. So, I
don't know how to check him out, but uh
thank you for the recommendation anyway.
I will find ways to check him
out. Okay. Arun says, "Why don't you
mention Jewish and Zionist lob in the
US?" Whenever talking about
unconditional support Israel gets from
the US, is there some other
reason? Which Jewish and Zionist lobbies
in the
US? Are there
any?
Look, there's no question that there are
lots of
influential Jewish origin politicians in
the
US. But if you
uh so there's no question about that.
But does that consider it a lobby? It
possibly could, but we don't have
evidence of that. And if you claim that
claim that it is a lobby without any
hard evidence of there being a formal
lobby and so on so forth, then you can
be called a conspiracy theorist, right?
And I have myself said that that if you
make claims that are not supported by
hard incontrovertible evidence, then you
are venturing into the realm of
conspiracy theory. And I prefer to stay
outside of the territory of conspiracy
theories.
So I do mention clearly that there is
unconditional support from the US
towards Israel. If you find that it's
not enough for you, maybe you can look
at somewhere else where somebody says
the things that you want want to hear.
That's all I can say.
Sir Zishan says the US is going to hold
a military parade in DC on Saturday. Are
military parades useful for any reason
or are they a waste of time and money
and ex
expenditure? Can US military parades
compete with May 9 or Chinese parades?
Is Trump a wannabe
dictator? Trump does have a very
controlling tendencies. Um he I'm sure
he would love to be a dictator, but I
don't think that he'll be allowed to be
a dictator. No chance. I'm sure he would
love to be one. First of all, he's too
old. I think he's already kind of too
old to be president, but yeah, sure. He
seems to have the energy thus far.
Hopefully, it lasts him another three
and a half years by the time he's done
with this term. One of the oldest ever
US presidents. Uh so, first of all, he's
too old for it. And secondly, u he won't
be allowed to to become a dictator, but
I'm sure he would love to be one. Now,
about the military parades, what are
military parades useful for them? They
there are they are symbolic gestures.
It's about communicating things to your
population. And it's about communicating
things to the world that look at our
military hardware. We have so and so
kind of military hardware. It's very
powerful. It's very, you know, oh
inspiring and so on. So it kind of sends
a message to your people to the domestic
population that you know we are we are
in safe hands. We've got tremendous
military hardware. You can rest assured
we can take on the whole world and it
raises the morale and confidence of the
people. That sort of thing. It sends a
message to the world you know this
nation is not to be messed with. They
have got such tremendous weapons and so
on. That sort of thing. It also makes
the armed forces feel great. You know,
we go and march and parade and everybody
looks at us and everybody applauds and
we look great and so on and so that sort
of thing. It's it's a fun activity to
do, you know, drill, you know, march in
unison and all that sort of thing. Um,
can a US military parade compete with
May 9 or Chinese parades? Well, they're
all different. They're all different.
The US doesn't hold uh regular military
parades. The Russians do it. The Chinese
do it. We also have a military parade in
India, right? uh the Republic Day
parade. Uh so parades are done for all
these various reasons and um I think
there is some kind of uh what do you
call it? My daddy biggest kind of
competition in this parades. Yes. Yes.
Some kind of strength measuring contest
let's say.
So I think in in those terms I think
Russia and China may may
may out out compete the US but the US
doesn't do it on a regular basis as as
far as I know.
Okay. Prudi Raj says, "Sir, I don't want
to I don't think we can go back to
dictatorship. Maybe a hybrid is as you
elect
low maybe a hybrid as you elect low but
upper or mostly selected. I don't think
once somebody gains power they long to
lose it. That applies to the general
public too, right? The general public
should not have power. General public is
not capable of handling power. The
average person is not capable of
handling power. They will not not know
what to do with it. they would misuse
it. Only a very few people can genuinely
handle power and use it in the right
way. Um but you know when the right
person is is in power, you don't want
them to lose
it. You don't want them to lose it. See
Lie Kuan Yu was in power as long as he
wanted eventually he relinquished it.
And when he relinquished power, I think
the whole of Singapore was upset and sad
to see to see that he is giving up
power. He was that kind of a guy. He was
no doubt a dictator but he was a
benevolent dictator. He was great for
his country. Similarly, we've had
monarchs in India who when they moved
on, when they abdicated or when they
died, people were were distraught to see
this happen. Right?
So ideally you want a
system that is such that it throws up
the best possible
people and only the right kind of people
are able to rise to the very top. We
don't have that system today. So if we
have a dictatorship based on the current
system it's going to throw up
monsters.
Yeah. If you really want a dictatorship
a monarchy you have to first clean up
the system and get rid of all the
garbage. Today's system is is designed
to throw up the worst people, the most
mediocre people. And it's a miracle we
have some good leaders today in this
country, especially at the very top.
It's a miracle. It's not because of the
system. It's despite the system that
this has happened. So maybe there is
there is something good somewhere. But
overall in today's system, if you have a
dictatorship, it'll be a bad thing
rather than a good thing. So um hybrid
system look India's dictatorships were
always hybrid
um India is the mother mother the
birthplace of democracy by the way by
the way it's not Greece that's the
birthplace of democracy what was Greek
Greek democracy like do you know
that 80% of Greek's population was
slaves the rest 20% maybe 50% were women
so they were not allowed to vote only
the nobles were allowed to vote vote and
they called only the male nobles who
were very wealthy people and slave
owners only they were allowed to vote
and they called that
democracy and Greeks emerged thousands
of years after we had our own systems of
voting and
ballots in India we always had a
dictator up top the emperor or the king
but at the lower levels at the ground
levels people could vote and they could
elect their own officials to take care
of their municipalities and districts
and all that. We had our own very unique
system. It was a hybrid system. So the
people could never vote to overthrow the
the the the emperor or the king. Okay?
You dare not do that. But you could vote
for your local officials and you could
get rid of them also if they did not
perform. That's how it was. It was a
hybrid system. That's a good
system. Okay. Vive Malvia says, "Was the
22nd amendment lobbyed and brought by
the US deep state?" What was the 22nd
amendment? Let's let's let's
uh find out. 22nd amendment. What is
this
thing? 22nd amendment. the number of
times a person can be elected to the
office of president of the US and this
was limited to two terms by the deep by
the by the 22nd amendment because you
had a guy who was elected I don't know
three times four times uh Roosevelt
Franklin D Roosevelt was he was elected
uh as president four times he was
elected to four terms as
president and uh the 22nd amendment
amendment was a direct response to
office because it was felt that it was
necessary to prevent presidents from
holding office for an extended period of
time. So the question that Vive is
asking is that was this 22nd amendment
lobbyed and brought forth by the US deep
state? What are my thoughts? Look, if
the US deep state exists, then it would
have a vested interest in ensuring that
no president becomes too powerful
because then that president would be
able to if if he was able to stay as
president for an extended period of
time, then he would be able to grab more
and more power, right? That's how it
power works. And then this this person
could become a viable threat to the deep
state if the deep state exists. So it
makes sense that if the deep state
exists, then it would want to have
something like the 22nd amendment
uh you know, brought into
being. So it's possible. Does the deep
state exist? I believe something like
the deep state does exist. I believe
that there is an extra democratic extra
constitutional uh center of power
somewhere in the US or somewhere
somewhere in the world that controls and
owns the United States. It does look
like
that. It does look like that, doesn't
it? So then if it exists then it would
want to exert as much control as
possible over the presidents. The
president's uh only role should be to
distract the world from where the real
power lies through their antics. And
that's what Trump is doing beautifully,
isn't he? Even Biden was doing it. He
was also very entertaining by being so
clueless. Um yeah, so it's possible that
the deep state was the author of the
22nd amendment. It's possible.
Uh, Priti says, "Am I missing something
in my thought process? Could you
elaborate please?" I mean, which thought
process? You must have asked me a
question a long time ago. I'm not sure.
Which question, sir? What What have you
asked? Let me go through the previous
questions that I have
seen Pruti Raj. Okay. I'm See, you ask
me a question, you give me the context.
I'm not I'm not able to understand what
you're asking me,
sir. Are you missing something in which
thought process? Which thought
process? How can I elaborate if I don't
know what you're asking, sir? Why is why
are you people sometimes so
frustrating? Give me the correct
information so that I can understand.
Okay, I'm moving on. Sorry.
Zishan says, "Is it fair to say the US
is the greatest country ever considering
its achievements in only 250 years of
existence? Does it prove that does this
prove the founders's vision ideology
being supreme compared to other
founders?" Well, it depends on how you
define greatness. If you define
greatness as the amount of control you
have over the world, the amount of power
you can project across the world, the
amount the extent to which you can
subjugate the world, if that is
greatness, then the US is the greatest
country ever, no question about it. If
technological achievements etc all of
that is part of that, then yes, sure, no
question. The US is the greatest country
ever, the greatest empire ever. It's not
the greatest country ever. The US is the
greatest empire that has ever existed.
It has surpassed the achievements of the
British Reich. Sorry, the British re the
the British
Empire. It has surpassed the
achievements of the Third
Reich. It has surpassed the achievements
of Chingish Khan. But he was just one
man by the way. Okay? It has surpassed
um Julius Caesar, Alexander, Napoleon,
etc.
It it essentially controls the entire
world more or
less to a very large extent. It had
there was a time when it had this
uniolar moment, didn't it? And right now
it is at the peak of its power. It's
never been more powerful than it is
right now. So from from this set of
measurements, the US is unquestionably
the greatest country ever. Uh does this
prove that the founders's vision
ideology was supreme? No. The founders
vision ideology was something else and
the US today is something else. The US
is not working you know running as per
the ideology of the original founders.
It has kind of deviated from that
ideology to a significant extent and
that is a matter for a different
discussion. It's a very lengthy
discussion. I can't take it over here
right now. For that you have to read the
constitution. You have to read uh the
declaration of independence.
you know read the
constitution and then you see uh whether
all of that all of those ideals are
still are still being uh followed
today. So that's a different matter.
Okay. Taraka Taraka Rama says what do
you think about Germany and India
diplomatic ties? Do you think the do you
think Germany is at the at the verge of
having another dictator? I don't think
Germany is anywhere near the verge of
having another dictator. Not at all.
What do I think about Germany, India,
diplomatic ties? They're okay. Okay.
Nothing great, nothing bad, nothing
special, nothing terrible. Okay.
Reasonably
good,
lukewarm, warmish,
etc. Yeah, that's what I think. I mean,
I I overall like Germany as a nation. I
think Germany is in terrible shape today
because of the kind of leaders they
have. They had better leaders in the
past
without I'm not referring to Mr. Painter
but overall they had better leaders in
the past and it'll be good for them to
have better leaders
again. Okay. Vidi says um how will Bat
deal with Axai? We will deal with
Axachin when the time comes for Axai.
Now is not the time for Axai. It's too
far. It's too far a bridge as of now.
MK says, "What did the CCP do
differently from the USSR to ensure
competent leadership succession despite
both having similar communist political
structures?" That's a great question.
They did a lot of things
differently. Uh they ensured there was
proper
merit meritocracy.
uh they
uh so for that you have to go back and
look at the history of how things went
right. So for the longest time you had
this
u you had the cult of Mao Mautum he was
like a god the red sun in the the sky
that was maong there's this Chinese song
okay very famous Chinese song red in the
red sun in the
sky so there was this whole this whole
cult movement that was created around
maong once he died they purged the party
of all his supporters they they p they
purged the party of of his life and so
on. And then a new set of leaders was
brought in and the whole the whole
system kind of changed and there was
this u focus on modernization, this
focus on on uh industrialization, this
focus on um putting aside the failed
policies of Mao and embracing
manufacturing and all of that and
keeping your head down, hiding your uh
hiding your strength and biting your
time, all of the ding chopping thing.
and they ensured that the right leaders
were always brought to the top and there
was tremendous tremendous competition
within the Chinese Communist Party for
rising to the top on the basis of
performance and merit. So it was a very
strongly meritocratic structure despite
being a complete dictatorship and there
was this tremendous u focus on
performance. So that's how the chi the
Chinese Communist Party operated and
there was a lot of change in China
because of this a lot of
progress and that's where the U USSR
differed from China. Uh it it was way
more corrupt than China. Allegedly China
also is also quite corrupt but uh in a
different way. So I think that's one key
difference. Virtual Venom. Thank you
very much
sir. And v virtual men venom again we
have a nuclear triad. Should we create a
fourth leg of military which has
multi-pace stations and can launch
attacks anywhere from the world,
anywhere in the world from there? Well,
we don't talk about such things because
you're not supposed to weaponize space.
But
yes, the US has a space force. The
Chinese have a rocket force and they
also may have a space force. Not sure if
the Russians have it. Why shouldn't we
have it? I think we have criminally
neglected space despite having such
tremendous capabilities. We launch the
PSLV
so so seldom that the last one or two
times it has we have tried launching it
it failed. See if we have a schedule a
weekly schedule that we are launching a
PSLV every every 7 days or 10 days then
this entire process of manufacturing the
rocket will become so welloiled that no
defects could possibly come into it. But
if you are launching just once or twice
or thrice a year then only once in a
while you're manufacturing it then you
will have flaws that creep in and that's
why the PSLV one of our most reli
reliable rockets has failed the last
time at least maybe couple maybe a
couple of
times. We are criminally neglecting our
space
sector. So I think it it would be great
to have a space force. It would be great
to have uh the the the ability to launch
heavy rockets with heavy payloads
comparable to what SpaceX does. SpaceX
has become the global leader now. ISRO
is like nothing compared to SpaceX,
right? When SpaceX started it was it was
nothing was a big deal. Uh so yeah,
that's the deal. So I think we should
have much greater space launch
capabilities and it what's wrong with
have with this
having military dimension also. So just
like an air force we should have a space
force and then we can look into further
uh details of what we can do with
that. So I think it's a great idea sir.
Jre Rebel Star says which will CA
profession be affected by AI like IT
field? Oh
absolutely
absolutely AI will wipe wipe out the CA
professions. Okay. I promise you sir. I
promise you if you're not careful you
will lose
everything if you are a CA.
I I I'm pretty sure if you take chat GPT
and and give it the Indian CL I mean the
the IT act and everything that that the
the legal corpus all texts that are
supposed to be applicable to the income
tax and all that and GST and all that.
I'm sure CH GP already has all of that
knowledge. I've never looked into it but
I'm sure it can act as a very competent
tax advisor and not just for an
individual probably for a company. So if
somebody purchases that $200 a month
subscription, I suppose they can use it
like you know like like an like an like
a CA itself for not just the person but
for an organization. I think the CA
profession could be wiped out by AI. So
if you're
smart, what you can do is a one person
CA firm, you are one person, but you
will provide services to dozens of of
companies and individuals as if you have
like 50 CAS working for you. You can do
that if you're smart. It's a great uh
business opportunity actually. But yeah,
for most CA it's going to wipe out their
field unfortunately.
James says, "Queen Victoria did a lot
for India. She built railways and so
much
more." Indeed, indeed she did. Yes. The
railways she built were the
infrastructure of occupation and
extraction. And Queen Victoria had this
incredible distinction. What was that?
She was the greatest drug trafficker in
history. Pablo Escobar was an amateur
compared to her. Let's let's let's look
this up, shall we? Let's look this up. I
think I have this somewhere.
Um advanced. Uh okay, let's let's Google
let's Google this together.
Okay. Yes. Let let's let's Google
Whoopsie.
Let's do an advanced Twitter
search. Okay.
Um,
Victoria and let's look at tweets from
my
account. Victoria. Let us
see. See, look here. British opium
warehouse in Patna
uh opium financed British rule in India.
The British forced Indian farmers to
cultivate opium instead of food crops
leading to horrific famines and the
deaths of
millions. Queen Victoria was the biggest
drug trafficker in history. After
creating artificial famines, the British
forced starving Indians to carry out
backbreaking hard labor in in return for
relief. So-called relief. This so-called
relief consisted consisted of less food
than the Nazis provided to the inmates
of the Buchanan death camp in World War
II. Check out these details. Okay, sir.
So that's about it for your beloved
Queen Victoria, Sir James Geopolitical
Dubet. Thank you so much, sir. Thank
you. Barava says, "Is the arms race the
biggest reason for the financial power
of the US or the work that they have
done on on their country? Does the US
have very high arms sales income?" Uh
we'll have to look into it, but it's one
of the major industries that they have.
um their financial power grew because of
the sales of arms and whatever else that
they did to all the nations during the
second world war and all the debt they
have collect collected from the UK or
other countries ever since the UK was
still paying debt until the beginning of
the 21st century apparently right and um
so that turned the US into a major
manufacturing superpower and then there
was the
Um that
1944 what was the
hotel? Oh, why does that name elude me?
the Breton Hall the Breton Woods
agreement in which the US dollar was
accepted by the rest of the world as the
global reserve currency and that was
another huge Phillip to the uh cementing
of the US as its its status as the
world's uh only world's major power
right uh and all of these all of these
things said together
uh put together contributed to the
financial power of the US. But what
really contributed to that is uh it's
it's taking over the the supply chains
and all the power projection structures
that the British Empire had created and
the US took it over and it expanded it
globally. So all of this took put
together contributed to the power of the
US. Financial power, military power,
hard power, all of this put together.
I'm not sure what the
uh arms sales the US uh has per year.
You would have to do a detailed piece of
research for that. Look at all the major
US arms um arms manufacturing companies
and then what are their annual sales the
past year and put it together and that
sort of thing. That will take time but I
suppose somebody could do
it. Uh Inferno GES says above a level do
flash points become fire
points? I have no idea what you mean by
that. Above a level, do flash points
become fire points? I'm not sure what
you're asking me, sir. I'm sorry. Not
able to
understand. Deep learner says, "Why does
the deep establishment want Islamic
political control to grow in Europe via
migrants? Isn't it better for them to
keep Christian influence?"
Why does the
deep political
establishment maybe because Islam is is
better from their perspective for
establishing control over populations
compared to Christianity. Maybe because
they see that Christianity has lost
relevance in Europe Europe which may be
pretty true and that's why the church is
trying to move its way eastwards
especially towards India. They want to
Christianize India and by that they want
to continue to hold sway over a large
percentage of the world's population
because Europe has kind of given up on
Christianity apparently which seems to
be pretty true. So now the old
establishment deep establishment they
want to find a new way to keep the
population under control. Maybe they
feel that Islam is much better for for
keeping people in line and under
control. So probably that is the
reason. Okay. Okay, Grock says, "Sarch
council of 300 experts say that they are
deep." Who are these
experts? Who are these experts? Anyway,
I I I will check it out. Maybe I know
about it. Have you considered that?
Maybe I know about things, but I prefer
probably not to talk about certain
things. Have you considered that
possibility?
Spade says Victoria my foot sar
s tan punt says what's your opinion onto
bismbach as a statesman did kaiser
Wilhham and Hitler destroy his
legacy great man otoan bbismar he
created an artificial nation in
1871 which was called deutscheland
Germany great man he took this
absolutely
jumbled this bits and pieces of counties
and duchies and little pieces of of of
of little kingdoms and states. He took
them all together and cobbled them into
this great German
nation. Great man, incredible man. the
iron chancellor and yes Kaiser
villain and then Hitler destroyed his
legacy. You're essentially spot
on. Purit sir, welcome sir. Ma'am,
welcome to membership and thank you so
much for becoming a member. I appreciate
appreciate that. I show speed donated $1
trillion. Well, that's outstanding. Um,
okay. My name is Aisha Speed. I love you
too, sir. I have you have incredible
knowledge about politics, geography,
history, all the things. Love you too. I
shout out Okay. Okay. Thank you so much.
I really appreciate your message and
your contribution. Thank you so much
sir. I I show
speed. MK are we focusing only on chip
fabs but not enough on displays, PCBs,
cameras, sensors, RAMs, other phone
components, fully electronic
sovereignty. We start somewhere then we
move on. We start somewhere. The
somewhere that you start with is the
core component. You don't start with
display. You start with the with the
heart, the brain. So I think we are
starting at the right place and
eventually we'll move out to everything
else. The other stuff is probably
easier. Of course, I'm not saying it's
easy. Displays are hard. LCDs and
whatever LEDs, whatever it is, uh I'm
not sure what PCBs is, but yeah,
sensors, RAM, all of that is is is tough
technology. I agree that we need to have
full electronic sovereignty. I think
right now we have focused we we have
decided to first focus on on chips. Get
that down. And then the other other
technologies are kind of related to that
kind of. So I think that's the that's
the uh way we're going to proceed with
the matter. Tak Tarak Rama becomes a new
member. Thank you so much. I really
appreciate uh you're becoming a member.
Thank
you. VS says I wish to meet you again.
Okay. Last time we met during the TJD
Pune summit, you were in a hurry. I was
in I'm in hurry. Sorry about that.
Uh uh my question uh could you describe
the mistakes committed by Hitler that
made him lose the the second world war?
First of all uh um not sure who I met a
million people there but uh well I hope
we meet again. Um so um the mistakes
committed by
Hitler. First of all what are the m okay
what are the mistakes? First of all he
chose to attack Russia before dealing
with the UK. maybe he should have
finished off the UK when it was possible
to do that.
um he had this big battle of London and
the battle of of England, the aerial
battles, but he kind of lost interest
and moved eastward
suddenly and that allowed the UK
breeding the breeding space in the time
to survive in the time to carry out the
operation against the French fleet which
convinced the Americans that the US UK
can be trusted and supported that sort
of thing and then so that's one big
mistake then Hitler went uh started
operation
Barbarosa targeting the the USSR but
instead of going straight for Moscow he
went towards the caucases to go go for
the oil fields. If he had gone straight
for Moscow and kept the Caucasus oil
fields full later they could have taken
Moscow but he chose to yeah even there
there was a mistake and when because of
this delay even a slight delay what
happens is that Russia punishes you.
It's it's who who punishes you? old man
winter that punishes you and the
punishment is that your your troops will
freeze to death in the tens of thousands
and that's what happened uh and so on
and the third mistake is that the Hitler
decided that he will fight everybody at
the same time I mean have some some kind
of sense of limits he had the same kind
of hubris that Napoleon had go and
conquer the whole world nothing is
enough for me it's never it's never
enough so these are some of the mistakes
that he made I would say he had such
tremendous engineers ers such tremendous
technology they developed but in still
he's cornered that so
bad uh Jay says how will Navi change
India's global leverage um it it's not
about leverage it's about uh atma
self-sufficiency in in 1999 during the
car cargle war the Americans switched
off GPS for India so we were left like
you know we could not suddenly we had to
find a different way to uh to to to to
acquire
targets. So this time during operation
synindur we may probably not have relied
on GPS. We had Navic and we had other
other redundancies as well built into
our uh our uh guidance systems. So Navic
is our own constellation of satellites
that that gives us GPS level u you know
navigation capabilities
uh and it's not a global thing. It's
still a it's still a regional thing. So
it's it's centered over the Indian
subcontinent and gives you coverage over
a over a broader geography slightly
beyond the Indian subcontinent. So it's
it's it's good enough for our purposes
but ideally we would like it to be a
global thing. So I think we should
launch more satellites and make it a
global constellation. So if you make it
a global consolidation, it'll it'll
allow us to be able to let's say send
[Music]
packages send packages ballistically
anywhere in the world with super super
crazy
accuracy. For example, during operation
synindor, we hit a target in uh Nurh
Khan air base from a distance of 400 500
km and that target was 45 cm wide and
our brahos which travels at 2 and a half
Mac hit that smack bang in the center.
So that's the kind of accuracy we have
with our missiles because of our
guidance systems. So if you have Navic
globally then we can deliver that sort
of pre precision globally.
So Arun says did you see the recent
Malia podcast? Any opinion on him? I
haven't seen the podcast. I don't watch
podcasts. I don't have the time to watch
podcast and this is supposedly a 4-hour
podcast and secondly it's not a topic
that interests me. So I haven't seen it.
I am not one going to watch it. uh I
don't look at all these little topics.
I'm sure it's a very big topic for a lot
of people. Don't miss I mean I'm I'm not
trying to disparrage that at all. I'm
sure it's very important for many people
and I totally respect that. It's not
important for me. I look at global
geopolitics. I look at things rel
related to that. So this is not on my
radar because of these reasons. So I
haven't seen it.
Spade says, "Sar, if China clashes with
the US in the future and gets weakened,
could we take back Akai Chin and what's
the probability of this happening? We'll
see about that." Look, it's like the P
question. Every day I get the question
about P. Um, we would love to have the P
back, but it depends on a variety of
factors. If China clashes with the US in
the future, becomes weakened. Well, it
depends on the parameters and dimensions
of the weakening and the specific
circumstances and if certain
circumstances are are met, we could take
back more than axim. So the probability
of that
happening I think this is significant
probability in the
next one flash point could be in 2027
the Taiwan thing maybe Xinping has a
deadline of 27. If that doesn't happen
then maybe maybe I don't know sometime
in the next 10 years that something may
happen but I can't say right now because
I haven't given sufficient thought
quantitatively to that. So I can't give
you probability as of now without proper
analysis. Bram thank you so much sir
ma'am thank you so
much. Abhishek once again thank you so
much to you as well. Uh Vidi says please
explain about the rainbow community and
find funding from elsewhere and why in
my profession we need to be affirmative.
Barat has always been all
accommodorative. The LGBTQ plus 235 etc.
community the the yeah those people um
well it's a group of people that exist.
It's not a group of people. I think out
of every 100,000 people a small
percentage of people may be like that.
They may have such uh such such
orientations. I'm sure that's pretty
much uh a given in any any population in
the world. And uh that's okay. There's
nothing right or wrong about it. Such
people exist and let them
exist. But why is this turned into a
movement? That is something that is the
west specializes in. Find some kind of
fringe movement and turn it into
something mainstream and use it to
achieve certain political agendas and
objectives. Right? U so that's what the
left has done in the west. They they
took over feminism and completely
completely utterly um hijacked it. They
took over the education system, utterly
hijacked it. They took over uh Marxism.
No, Marxism was already taken over.
What? What? They took over liberalism
and hijacked it. They have taken over
every possible movement and hijacked it.
They've taken over race rights
u civil rights movement and they've
hijacked that also in the US. Um and
obviously they've taken over the the I'm
sure in the US in the west uh gay people
were horribly oppressed because of the
religion and the culture of the west
after the destruction of the native
polytheism. So after abrahamism and
after Christianity became the pro
prominent religion and culture in the
west gay people were horribly oppressed
for centuries and the same was true in
the US and that's why there was the gay
rights movement but then the leftists
hijacked that and then they are funding
it to have to have whatever to further
whatever political agenda of theirs. So
uh we have in in Bharat we have always
been a commoditive. There is absolutely
the the leftists the Marxists hate us
right they hate Hinduism they hate
Indian culture and civilization but they
have never been able to find one shred
of evidence. They would love to find it
but they've not able to find it. They
would love to find a shred of evidence.
So there's no evidence that we have ever
uh oppressed the LGBTQ plus etc people.
They have always existed and we have
never bothered them and we have never
come in their way of living their life.
As long as you don't bother us, we'll
not bother you. Simple. Live and let
live which has always been our
philosophy. So that's the
deal. Ryik Patnak says views on I I
don't watch this stuff sir. Thank you.
What? You want me to to react to videos
now? Are you serious sir? I don't watch
this stuff. I look at geopolitics,
history, science, etc. What is all this?
Adwit says views on mega prison in El
Salvador and its leader. It's a prison
for terrorists and drug cartel, drug
mafia members and all who are
terrorizing society. So I think it's
when you have a terrorist population
that is terrorizing your society, you
got to lock them up. So that's what Mr.
Naib al-Buk has done and good job I
would say.
Okay. In terms of sheer criminality and
devastation brought on humanity, how
would you compare the US and the
UK? Okay. Now, you asking me to talk
about something very
controversial. I think this is something
that will have to be quantified and and
I cannot give you an off off the cuff
remark because it's a very serious
topic.
uh if you want to accuse the US and the
UK of being criminal, which I'm sure is
justified, but if you want to do that,
you have to back it up with facts,
figures, and hard numbers. And at this
point in time, off the cuff, I don't
have the facts, figures, and hard
numbers with me. So, I'll take a pass on
this question. But if you I think the UK
has started it and the US has US has
continued it because the US has
inherited them the
empire. Backbenture academy says was
once again I don't take Indian politics
questions so
pass uh views on water from industry to
India. I think the water is great. We're
going to use it. We're going to
replenish our dry states. We're going to
pass it to Rajasthan. We're going to
pass it to Hana Punjab. we can send it
all the way to Kutch if required in in
in western Gujarat and it's going to be
beautiful. It's going to beautify our
land. It's going to create more farmland
and all that for us and uh and yeah it's
going to be great for us. We're going to
do all this in the next 10 years and
Pakistan will pay the consequences for
its decades long support for
terrorism. Uh why did Britain kneel
before Nazis despite ruling the largest
empire? Did the US correct the mistakes?
That mistake the British never kneled
against the Nazis before the Nazis. We
will fight on the beaches. We'll fight
here. We'll fight there. We'll not will
not give in. That's the great speech,
right? That's that Winston Churchill is
remembered for. The British did not
kneel. They fought they fought with the
support of the US. The US kept on
replenishing their supplies and food,
wood stuffs and whatnot. And the British
kept on fighting. No question about it.
The British did not kneel before the
Nazis and eventually they were able to
launch the Normandy invasion from from
Britain and the Americans were the were
at the forefront of that. But most of
the fighting and most of the dying and
most of the winning was done by the
Russians, the
Soviets. Chira Sha, thank you very much.
Thank you. Watabalaji says why India not
interested in quantum computing? I think
we we have already developed one quantum
computer and we are in the process of
taking this very seriously. So yeah, I
think we are on the right track now.
Okay, we are almost at the end of
today's live stream. So I would request
everybody to stop asking questions.
Whatever is left, I'll take it quickly.
Dr. Ritwick says, "Once we take back P,
what will happen to the locals of the
region? Will they be deported back to
Pakistan or will they be given Indian
citizenship?" That's a great question
and this is something we will be we will
have to address when it when we come to
it. Uh it's it's I don't think it's very
feasible to deport them to
Pakistan out of out of uh land that
they've been living it for living in for
decades. On the other hand, many of them
are actually outsiders who have been
brought in by Pakistan. So it's going to
be a complicated scenario and it's given
it's it's guaranteed that they these P
locals are going to be very radicalized
against us. So it's going to be very
complicated but we're going to have to
find a proper solution for that and the
government will have certain uh plans in
mind for this. Tanmay Pant says why
Japanese lost to commodor Perry Tokugawa
lost all goodwill after the after and
soon after and soon Miji took over. Okay
I um it's been too long since I read
about this so I don't remember about
this. say this particular incident
Tokugawa lost all goodwill maybe I'll
I'll I'll have to answer this question
at a future point in time this time
right now my memory of this period of
history is hazy my memory of the post
maji period the major restoration post
that is is sharper right now so I won't
be able to answer this question
sorry okay Shubam Dubet says the PM's G7
visit is crucial especially amid
potential internal propaganda and
Kalistthani agendas. It must align
strategically with his
objectives views on this move
internationally. I don't think it's a
crucial move. I think we are able to
achieve all of our all of our um
national objectives through bilateral
uh you know bilateral meetings and
bilateral uh uh proceedings with various
nations. But it's always good for the
Indian prime minister to participate in
these multilateral uh events because you
get to get the sense of what everybody
is thinking, what everybody is talking
about and you got to meet everybody else
and u it's always good to do this. So um
it's it's
it's not crucial in the sense that it
would have been a great game changer or
or a dealbreaker if he did not go but
it's very good that he's going and uh
I'm sure it aligns strategically with
his objectives and he's going to it's
going to be great for India.
Yeah. Dr. Ritik Pnag says tell me
probably year I can go I can plan a trip
to Hunza Valley Kard and Abatab and
Atabad Lake entire Gilgadasan is our
territory.
Okay. Should I should I venture a year?
Today is 2025. Which year can you plan a
trip to Hunza Valley? Let's say 2030.
Let's say let's say
2030. Warrior says, "Can we get Axaiin
back?" We can, but I'm not sure when we
can, and we will. I promise you we will.
Okay, with that, we are at the end of
today's live stream.
So, so thank you very much everybody for
all your questions. Okay, let me take
one question by Makloven and where is
it? Mloan says an Australian journalist
was shot by cops live on camera in LA
and they say India doesn't have press
freedom.
I know. I saw that clip on X I think
today sometime. Um an Australian
journalist was doing a news report on
live on camera and this American cop
just turns towards her and shoots her.
Bang. He shoots her with a rubber
bullet. But what on earth was that brute
of a person thinking? Shooting somebody,
a lady who's clearly a
journalist. These people are absolute
brutes. the US is a police state and
that's how they treat journalists and
then they claim India doesn't have any
press freedom. What a joke it is.
Anyway, so I'm glad you you pointed this
out. Okay, with that we are at the end
of today's live stream. Thank you very
much everybody. I hope this was uh
hopefully you learned something from
this and gained some knowledge from
this. So please keep asking questions,
please keep learning. Please keep
raising your standards and I will see
you in the next one. Thank you so much.
Good night. Good day everywhere.
Everyone wherever you are. I'll see you
soon.